5.
It's not ever said left here, and this lesson I will show you how to personalize your
Chi-GPT using custom instructions.
It's a simple but powerful way to make Chi-GPT feel like your personal assistant.
So, let's first go to your settings, click on profile, settings, and open personalization
tab.
So, first we need to check that your customization is enabled by this toggle.
Ok, let's talk about this customization.
Let's let you tell Chi-GPT who are you, what tools you use, and how you want to respond.
So, it's like setting the guard the ground rules for your personal EIS system.
Once you feel them, in Chi-GPT starts giving answers at much your exact style.
Your stack, your needs without having to repeat them every time.
So, personalization also saves time so you don't need to explain your technical stack
on every chart what tools you use, what preference you want, what don't you want Chi-GPT
speak, so you can set up at once and use it later.
So, Chi-GPT remembers them and keep answers consistent.
You can also add the own rules like "Never guess" or "verify answers" before sending
it to me or avoid some outdated syntax for code.
So, this small details make a really big difference, especially when you code daily and need
past reliable help.
So, you can see in the custom instruction as your way to train Chi-GPT to speak your developer
language.
Once you set it, it becomes the code and partner, it will work faster, smarter, and fully
align it with your style of work.
So, let's go one by one.
The first setting is Chi-GPT personality, you can have different options, so it lets you
pick up the tone and communication style, so Chi-GPT will use to respond to you.
The default one is a normal and friendly, which I recommend you to live.
The sonic is critical and sarcastic style might be negative, the robot is really short,
direct and efficient, it's normally used for coding, because it's clear and fast.
The listener is calm and supportive, so it depends what mood you'd like.
Because the nerd is excited about tech and the tale, it's really enthusiastic, so it depends
what you'd like to use.
I recommend you to use default, because if you're doing not only coding and a few types
of work like you ask personal questions to coding, and for example, write some blog articles,
I recommend you use default, because it will adopt your needs.
The next one is custom instructions, so what is custom instructions?
This is where you can set rules, how Chi-GPT should behave, what rules should follow.
I prepared a list of rules, I'll paste, so you can also copy paste them, so Chi-GPT will
use simple, clear and short language, it will never guess, it will always verify
before answering, it will be 100% honest, as much as he can be, if he ensures he should
say I don't know, if my question is unclear, he should ask follow-up questions first.
Then I described the technical stack I used to react with functional components in Java
script, I asked to avoid some boilerplate code and audit syntax, and always use modern
to leave code, never use short variables names, always use clear descriptive ones, and
the next setting is about different type of work I'm doing, so when explaining code of
theory, use short bullet points or quick summaries to don't waste my time, when comparing
tools or libraries give objective facts not opinions, when given recommendations, explain
why it's one short line, when writing code follow best practices, keep it clean and
modern, when it writing test, use witnessed and direct testing library with realistic examples,
when do the factoring keeps the logic same, don't change anything, don't ask, and explain
why it was better, so when reviewing and optimizing my code, show cleaner faster or more
readable alternatives, and when do the bargain, explain what was wrong, what happens and
show the fixed code, and of course when do documentation write some simple summaries and
clear just doc format or read me text, so this is the rules you can use for the start later
on when you will be, when you will understand what works for you and what don't, or you
can update them, so as an nickname you can use your name, so we can, it can call you with
your name, occupation, it's your job title or main role, I am a front-end developer, or
engineer, it's like, you will see here are, so more about you, this is a very, you can
write for you, what you do, what your context, I also prepared a few sentences that I build
to web applications using React, Nexus and JavaScript, I won't charge you to help me write
clean code, the bug issues, do the factoring of the logic and explain solutions in the
most simple way, so this is the personalization sentence I want to cover in this lesson,
if you follow this, if you feel this custom instructions, so you see the difference how
better he will respond, he will be in the context of tools, what you're using, so what
was really useful for you, all this custom instructions you can find in the lessons, and
see you in the next lesson.